<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Associaton of Citizens' Councils of Mississippi:Fourth Annual Report July 1958</title>
            <author>Association of Citizens' Councils of Mississippi</author><respStmt><resp>Editor</resp> <name>Margaret Gregory</name></respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Encoded for Digital Humanities 630 Spring 2023, Texas A and M University</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Association of Citizens' Councils of Mississippi, "Association of Citizens' Council of Mississippi, 4th
               Annual Report" (1958). Pamphlets and Broadsides. 6.
               https://egrove.olemiss.edu/citizens_pamph/6  University of Mississippi, eGrove</p></sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <front>
         <docAuthor>ASSOCIATION OF CITIZENS' COUNCILS OF MISSISSIPPI</docAuthor>
         <!-- States Rights : Racial Integrity -->
         <!-- Greenwood, Mississippi -->
         <docTitle>
            <titlePart type="main"> 4th Annual Report July 1958</titlePart>
            <titlePart type="sub">In Retrospect</titlePart>
         </docTitle>
         <!-- State Executive Committee and Officers -->
         <div type="officers">
            <listPerson>
               <person><persName ref="#person001">J.O. Sams</persName><residence>Columbus</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person002">John B. Cunningham </persName><residence>Brooksville</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person003">N.E. Dacus </persName><residence>Tupelo</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person004">Shelby Woodward </persName><residence>Louisville</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person005">Z.M. Veazey, Jr. </persName><residence>Coldwater</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person006">W.H. Anderson </persName><residence>Ripley</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person007">Ben Jack Hilbun </persName><residence>Oxford</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person008">John Tabor </persName><residence>Winona</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person009">A.E. Britt </persName><residence>Indianola</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person010">Wilburn Hooker </persName><residence>Lexington</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person011">Fred Jones </persName><residence>Inverness</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person012">Pete Williams, Sr. </persName><residence>Clarksdale</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person013">Tom P. Brady </persName><residence>Brookhaven</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person014">Albert Gardner </persName><residence>Yazzo City</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person015">Clay Tucker </persName><residence>Woodville</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person016">Ellis W. Wright </persName><residence>Jackson</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person017">W.H. Johnson, Jr. </persName><residence>Decatur</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person018">R.C. Bradshaw </persName><residence>Pearl</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person019">H.H. Harpole </persName><residence>Philadelphia</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person020">Marion Simpson </persName><residence>Canton</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person021">Dewey Myers </persName><residence>Prentiss</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person022">Ward Hurt </persName><residence>Lumberton</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person023">Robert Oswald </persName><residence>Pascagoula</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person024">J.E. Stockstill </persName><residence>Picayune</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person025">R.P. Parish </persName><occupation>State Treasurer <!-- Pres. Bank of Greenwood --></occupation><residence>Greenwood</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person026">Ellett Lawrence </persName><occupation>Finance Chairman</occupation><residence>Greenwood</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person027">Robert B. Patterson </persName><occupation>Executive Secretary</occupation><residence>Greenwood</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person028">W. J. Simmons </persName><occupation>Administrator</occupation><residence>1014 Plaza Building Jackson</residence></person>
               <person><persName ref="#person029">Mrs. Sara McCorkle </persName><occupation>Women's Divison</occupation><residence>Greenwood</residence></person>      
            </listPerson></div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <p>The fourth anniversary of the birth of your Citizens' Council movement-was quietly observed on <date>July 11, 1958</date>. It is fitting that those of us who have taken part in the resistance movement against forced integration look back over the past four years and make an appraisal of the situation then and the situation now.</p>
         <p>How successful have our efforts been, combined with those of many thousands of other patriotic Americans?</p>
         <p>Let's hear from some nationally recognized sources: From the Washington Post Times-Herald, dated <date>March 21, 1957</date>, by the managing editor,<persName>Alfred Friendly</persName></p>
         <p>"Segregationists in the Deep South have won the first round against racial intermixture in the public schools."...."The South has built a strong set of obstacles blocking the road to future integration. Here is the fruit of the segregationists' energetic and skillful work:</p>
         <p>1. THE principle of uncompromising segregation has been made to reign without effective challenge in state and local politics. With exceptions interesting only as curiosities, Deep South politicians do not and cannot breathe a public word to the contrary.</p>
         <p>2. MODERATES-those who oppose overnight and large-scale school integration but who nevertheless believe that some steps should be taken in the next few years leading to admission of some Negro students to hitherto white schools-have been placed on the defensive, so much so that they are scarcely to be heard in public. There is almost no debate. Only rarely is there a white voice raised in the press. the pulpit and the universities suggesting some forthright movement toward desegregation.
            And needless to say, the white man who spe'aks out directly for prompt integration is virtually a sideshow freak. </p>
         <!--Not sure what this is- it's like a sub heading in the list--><p>HOLD COMMUNITY REINS </p>
         <p>3. AT LEAST in its outward forms, leadership of community institutions such as state and local offices, the press, the church and the civic, welfare, service and social organizations is predominantly in the hands of the unyiellding segregationists. </p>
         <p>4. THE movement which had taken place since World War II toward interracial cooperation and toward some kinds of integration has been brought almost to a halt .... </p>
         <p>5. THE phrase of the "Liberal Underground"-a name wryly bestowed upon themselves by those who would like to see prompt movement toward compliance is that "the channels of communication are down." .. People of differing views on the race issue simply don't discuss them with each other, much less publicly debate them. </p>
         <p>6. THE Supreme Court decision has been repainted to appear as an order for instant and complete school integration, everywhere, in every school, in massive amount. When the white South now says, as it does with virtual unanimity. "It can't be done/' the "it" is automatically understood as
            meaning a Supreme Court decision for immediate and fullscale -intetmixtlrre of white and Negro students....</p>
         <!-- This is like a sub heading in the list --><p>A SPREADING CONCEPT </p>
         <p>SIGNIFICANTLY, that view of what "it" means appears to have been made into the dominant image in the rest of the Nation, too.</p>
         <p>The importance of that conception, of course, is that once it has been embraced, consciously or subconsciously, as what the Supreme Court ordered, the Southern position of "It can't be done" has to be conceded.. For good reasons or for bad ones, large scale integration of all Southern elementary and high schools seems, to almost all observers, Northern or Southern, as out of the question in the immediate future. </p>
         <p>7. A REGIONAL gospel has been established that any Federal attempt to force integration will be met by closing down the public school system. The farther south you go, the slighter is the action that is deemed to be "forced integration. </p>
         <p>The state of affairs outlined above did not just happen. It was planned that way, and with great skill. It was the achievement of deterulined, energetic and effective men. Some were organized formally in such 'groups as the White Citizens Councils: others acted informally, but no less effectively, in political or community groups. </p>
         <p>The speed of their work, the completeness of their control of Political bodies and agencies at all levels, their seizure of the offensive and their deftness in framing the issue in the terms they wanted-all this bespeaks a high order of skill and technique. ....</p>
         <p>THERE ARE parallels in the quick shifts of governmental, press and community attitudes in all the Deep South states. In many places there appears to have been a moment, whether of a few days or a few months duration, when leaders of opinion-not necessarily or even usually the political figures-were prepared, although reluctantly and unhappily, to take some first tentative measures leading to full compliance in the next several years. </p>
         <p>Then something happened. The mood passed to be replaced by an adamant resistance led and controlled by the segregationists, mililant and well-organized." </p>
         <p>From the Saturday Evening Post, <date>June 15, 1957.</date> Article entitled "The Deep South Says Never." The first of a series of five. </p>
         <p>...."Thus was formed the first Citizens' Council, a movement that in a few months swept the South and gave loud voice to the Southern resistance to school desegregation.</p>
         <p>At that time desegregation seemed inevitable and not far off. Today, in the Deep South, it seems unlikely in the foreseeable future. At that time the South was divided, perplexed, resigned. Today the Solid South is a fact, and its resistance to desegregation is granitic. Let us study the remarkable achievement of a resistance movement that has uncompromisingly set its face against the mainstream of American thought as expressed by the Supreme Court of the land - and has thus far got away with it." </p>
         <p><persName ref="#person030">Issac Toubin</persName>, of<placeName ref="#place001">New York</placeName>, Executive Director of the American Jewish Congress said at Miami Beach in <date>May of 1958,</date></p>
         <p>"We must face the fact that there is a real possibility of ultimate defeat in the struggle to end racial segregation. The proponents of m'usive resistance in :the South are not fighting for delay or moderation. Their aim is reversal in law, or nullification in fact, of the Supreme Court's decision." </p>
         <p>You who have been members and friends of the resistance movement know what you have done. You know what your local organization has done, and you have a good idea of what your State Association, and also the nation wide organization known as ''The Citizens' Councils of America," has accomplished. </p>
         <p>YOU realize that the Citizens' Council Organization was the rallying point for popular resistance to the unconstitutional "integration" decision of the Supreme Court. You have seen resistance grow from timid faltering efforts on the part of a few individuals to "massive" resistance with the full power of the state governments taking constitutional action towards protecting their people and their schools from destruction. Often, for the individual member, "it is hard to see the forest for the trees." It is hard to picture yourself as an important cog in this gigantic movement, but without you the movement cannot succeed. </p>
         <p>One member observed that "It's not only what we did here in <placeName ref="#place002">Mississippi</placeName>. It's what our organization inspired people in other states to do that really turned the tide. Resistance is contagious."</p>
         <div type="article"> 
            <head>Remember Little Rock</head>
            <p>The greatest encounter between the constitutional rights of the people and the states vs. the usurped powers by the Federal Government occurred at <placeName ref="#place003">Little Rock</placeName> "Remember <placeName ref="#place003">Little Rock</placeName>" is the battle cry for people who believe it is their sacred right to' educate their children in their own way without interference from politically motivated federal sources who know little of local conditions. Because of what happened
               in <placeName ref="#place003">Little Rock</placeName>, Americans everywhere were made aware of the vicious determination of the so-called "liberal minority groups" in their obsession to force their will upon those who differ. The entire nation owes a debt of gratitude to the patriotic citizens of <placeName ref="#place003">Little Rock</placeName>, who refused to bow to the
               tyranny of forced integration. </p> </div>
         <div type="article">
            <head>NEITHER SUDDENLY NOR GRADUALLY</head>
            <p>The danger of sudden integration may have passed, but there is great danger, now that the frontal attack by the mongrelizer s failed that the will resort to "infiltration" and "gradualism." </p>
            <p>Southern observers who have watched neighborhood integration in the North now realize that "Being a little bit integrated is like being a little bit pregnant." There is no such thing as being a little bit integrated. Our Northern friends are horrified to find that their original concession to "a little integration" has inevitably forced them to' give up their homes and flee to the suburbs. The flight continues, and where it will stop no one knows. </p> </div>
         <div type="article"> 
            <head>MIGRATION</head>
            <p>For economic and other reasons, brought about by selfish politicians and misinformed "do-gooders," the Negro" migration to the North has increased and will continue to increase. The end result of this migration will help our cause, but we feel for our Northern white citizens. Already in many Northern sections innocent white people are being forced to suffer a second "reconstruction" such as our ancestors suffered eighty-five years ago. This is tragic. History proves, however, that the masses of people have never reacted to logic and common sense, but only to chaos and bitter experience. The best cure for "integration and Negro domination" is "integration and Negro domination," although it is a painful one that leaves many permanent scars. In many areas "the situation will have to get worse before it gets better."</p>
         </div>
         <div type="article"> 
            <head> RACIAL SEPARATION </head>
            <p> The South respectfully submits that the best method by which the two races can occupy the same geographical area with a minimum of racial conflict is through the time honored and history proven expedient which is called "segregation." </p>
         </div>
         <!-- THis is a different heading than my other div articles <div type="article">
            <head>THE ROAD AHEAD</head> -->
         <div type="article"> 
            <head>ORGANIZATION</head>
            <p> The only method by which racial separation can be continued is through local, state and natiQnal organization, in order that the many powerful organizations which seek mongrelization can be counteracted. Many organizations dedicated to racial separation have started in the North and West, and there will be many more in the years ahead. Many of these organizations are not called "Citizens' Councils," but "a rose by any other name would smell as sweet," and their purpose is basically the same as ours.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="article">
            <head>POLITICS </head>
            <p>The Citizens' Council is not a political organization, but in our form of government it is natural that sentiment in favor of racial separation will express itself politically by one method or another. This is already evident in the South, and will be evident in Northern and Western areas' eventually. </p>
         </div>
         <div type="article">
            <head>OUR EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE </head>
            <p>Listed on page 1 are the members of our Executive Committee. Four Executive Committeemen are elected to serve from each one of our six Congressional Districts. This election is held at the annual district meeting of county chairmen in each district. These are the men who set the policy and direct our State Association. Your State Executive Committee meets the third Thursday in each month, in <placeName ref="#place004">Jackson, Mississippi</placeName>, at one of the hotels there. It is always a dutch luncheon meeting. This group provides the personal contact necessary so that your Association will be truly representative of the local Citizens' Councils in the state. We ask that you note the name of your Executive Committeeman, so that you can get in touch with him at any time. </p>
            <p>We have urged the board of directors of each local organization to hold a similar monthly meeting. The holding of these regular meetings provides a constant, competent body to deal with any local problems that may arise, and has led in every case to a strong local organization. </p>
         </div>
         <div type="article">
            <head>OUR EDUCATIONAL PROGRAM </head>
            <p>Your State Executive Committee has engaged an outstanding lady, <persName ref="#person029">Mrs. Sara McCorkle</persName>, to direct Women's activities in connection with the Citizens' Council movement throughout the state, and to direct the <affiliation>Citizens' Council educational program</affiliation> for the youth of <placeName ref="#place002">Mississippi</placeName>. <persName ref="#person029">Mrs. McCorkle</persName> has made many talks to various Civic organizations throughout the state and to many ladies' organizations. She assists the local Citizens' Councils in carrying on educational programs for the young people in the community, in giving the facts concerning race and the reasons for the South's policy of racial separation. She directs our annual essay contest among high school students. </p>
         </div>
         <div type="article">
            <head>THE CITIZENS' COUNCIL FORUM </head>
            <p>We now have the Citizens' Council Forum television program in nine Southern states, on at least seventeen different stations, and we have the Citizens' Council Forum radio programs on more than one hundred radio stations throughout the South. The idea is to inform our people, here in the
               South, as to the true facts concerning "integration" and to present the South's case to the nation. As soon as possible, we intend to expand this program to cover the entire nation. <persName ref="#person031">Bill Simmons</persName>, as the producer of these programs, is doing a magnificent job. He maintains a complete staff at our <placeName ref="#place004">Jackson</placeName> office in the Plaza Building</p>
         </div>
         <div type="article">
            <head>OUR OWN NEWSPAPER </head>
            <p>Since October, 1955, we have been publishing our own monthly newspaper, which acts as the official organ for the Citizens' Councils of America movement. We have never missed an issue, and we urge the local organizations to subscribe for each member, so that the local membership will have an idea about what is going on state wide and nationally. </p>
            <p>We have found that the most economical means of keeping our members informed and of penetrating the paper curtain which in the past has' kept the truth from the public is through this fine publication. All of us are proud of the fine job that <persName ref="#person031">Bill Simmons</persName> has done as editor of our official organ. </p>
            <p>Local Councils that have subscribed to our newspaper for each of their members find that they are well informed and are kept interested in this movement. Our members in <placeName ref="#place002">Mississippi</placeName> are urged to mail their copies of the newspaper to friends and relatives in the North after they have read it each month. </p>
            <p>We certainly hope that next year each Council will subscribe to our newspaper for each of its members. The subscription price has been set at $1.00 per year for members in lots of 50 or more subscriptions, the lowest figure ossible, since no advertising is accepted. For single subscribers the subscription price is $2.00 per year. </p>
            <p>If preferred, you may send your subscription direct to The Citizens' Council, <placeName ref="#place004">1014 Plaza Building, Jackson, Miss.</placeName> </p>
         </div>
         <div type="article">
            <head>OUR STATE OFFICE </head>
            <p>Our state office in <placeName ref="#place005">Greenwood</placeName>employs, in addition to the Executive Secretary and Director of Women's Activities, four full time employees to handle national correspondence, educational publications, and administrative organizational work. Our office receives as high as 300 letters per week from fortyeight states and many foreign countries. All inquiries are answered and orders for literature are filled promptly</p>
            <p>We carry on an active correspondence with Citizens' Councils and other organizations all over the United States. We exchange information and carryon liaison with all sincere patriotic groups and individuals who are dedicated to constitutional government. We have mailed over five million pamphlets to key individuals and organizations in every state in the union and in most foreign countries. These pamphlets, by prominent and respected authorities, present the case for the South, states' rights and racial integrity. </p>
            <p>Three years ago it was clearly evident that most of the national magazines were slanting news stories against the South. Lately, we have noticed a reluctant leakage of truth concerning the United States Supreme Court and the Negro race from even such rabid anti-South publications as Time and Life. </p>
            <p>Negro migration to the North and the determined presentation of facts by Southerners has helped to bring about this phenomenon. </p>
         </div>
         <div type="article">
            <head>THE CITIZENS' COUNCILS OF AMERICA</head>
            <p>The Citizens' Councils of America was organized in <placeName ref="#place006">New Orleans</placeName> in <date>January, 1956 </date>, with individuals from eleven Southern States participating. It has held regular semi-annual meetings each year since that time</p>
            <p>We believe that this organization will continue to serve as an effective coordinating agency and information center for the various state groups. Our office in <placeName ref="#place005">Greenwood</placeName> is the national administrative headquarters. </p>
            <p><persName ref="#person027">ROBERT B. PATTERSON,</persName> Executive Secretary </p> 
         </div>
         <div type="article">
            <head>WHAT YOU CAN DO AS AN INDIVIDUAL</head>
            <p>1. Study all the facts which give concrete reasons why the
               South and the nation must maintain its racial integrity. You
               cannot do your part in educating your children, relatives, friends, neighbors and business associates unless you know
               the facts. Subscribe to publications which give the truth about
               integration. In order to counteract the propaganda campaign
               against us, we must carry on a continuous educational program and you can help. </p>
            <p>2. Join a worthwhile organization dedicated to constitutional government and racial integrity such as the Citizens' Council. Be a good member and remember that your dues and your efforts are the keys to victory. This is your fight. Organized aggression must be met with organized resistance. </p>
            <p>3. Enlist additional members for your local organization.
               Educate your fellow citizens so that we may all stand together. Contact friends in other counties and states and encourage them to organize. Remember, the mongrelizers are well organized and highly financed. </p>
            <p>4. Keep informed of all efforts to integrate the races. In
this manner a mobilized public opinion may express itself from every direction against every attempt at integration. </p>
            <p>5. Write letters expressing your views to newspapers, and
               magazines, as well as to your local, state and national officials. Your letter combined with thousands of others will have
               a resounding effect. </p>
            <p>6. Vote for those seeking public office who actively and
               honestly resist the integration of the races. This also includes
               your school board and the governing body of your church. </p>
            <p>7. Be alert for all propaganda movements towards integration, whether in the theatre, television, radio, athletic events,
               schools, newspapers, magazines, books, or the church. These
               programs are cleverly planned to soften our people to the
               idea of mixing of the races. If you should cancel a subscription or withhold patronage, give your reason. </p>
            <p>8. Be sure you know what is being taught your children in
               School and Church.</p>
            <p>9. Stand firnlly in the right. Let everyone know that you
               stand for segregation of the races. </p>
            <p>10. There are scalawags among us today just as there were
               in reconstruction days-people who live among us and thrive
               upon us, but who are willing to sell us out to the mongrelizers.
               Integrationists who live among us are much more dangerous
               to our cause than those who live in <placeName ref="#place001">New York</placeName> or <placeName ref="#place007">Illinois</placeName>. </p>
            <div type="list">
               <head>Publications <lb/>All Literature Postpaid <lb/> Pamphlets</head>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <title>The Supreme Court Must Be Curbed</title> By <name><persName ref="#person032">James F. Byrnes</persName></name>
                  </item>
                  <item><title>A Christian View on Segregation</title> By <name><persName ref="#person033">Rev. Guy T. Gillespie</persName></name></item>  
                  <item><title>The Ugly Truth About the NAACP</title> By <name><persName ref="#person034">Atty. Gen. Eugene Cook</persName></name></item>
                  <item><title>We've Reached Era of Judicuial Tyranny</title> By <name><persName ref="#person035">Senator James O. Eastland</persName></name></item>                 <item><title>The Citizens' Council</title> By <name><persName ref="#person027">R. B. Patterson</persName></name></item>                 <item><title>A Jewish View on Segregation</title> By <name>Anonymous</name></item>                 <item><title>Segregation and the South</title> By <name><persName ref="#person013">Judge Tom P. Brady</persName></name></item>                 <item><title>The Mid-West Hears the South's Story</title> By <name><persName ref="#person028">W. J. Simmons</persName></name></item>                 <item><title>Congressional Committee Report on What Happened when Schools were Integrated in Washington D. C.</title> From <name>Congressional Record</name></item>                 <item><title>Where is the Reign of Terror?</title> By <name><persName ref="#person036">Congressman John Bell Williams</persName></name></item>                 <item><title>Mixed School and Mixed Blood</title> By <name><persName ref="#person037">Herbert Ravenel Sass</persName></name></item>                   <item><title>The Educational Fund of the Citizens' Council</title> By <name><persName ref="#person026">Ellett Lawrence</persName></name></item>  
                  <item><title>Second Annual Report</title> <name>Detailed organizational plan</name></item>     
               </list>
            </div>
            <div type="list">
               <head>Rubber Stamps </head>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <title>"Remember Little Rock"</title> <measure type="price">$2.00 each</measure></item>
                  <item>
                     <title>"Brotherhood by Bayonet</title> <measure type="price">$2.00 each</measure></item>
               </list>
             </div> 
            <div type="list">
               <head>Books</head>
               <list>
               <item><title>Black Monday</title> By <name><persName ref="#person013">Judge Tom P. Brady</persName></name><measure type="price">$1.00</measure></item> 
                  <item><title>The Deep South Says Never</title> (paperback edition) by <name><persName ref="#person038">John Bartlow Martin</persName></name><measure type="price">.35</measure></item> </list>
               <div type="part"><p> The above may be had by writing the Citizens' Council, <placeName ref="#place005">207 West Market Street, Greenwood, Mississippi.</placeName> See that your public and school libraries obtain these books. </p></div>              
            </div>
            <div type="list">
               <head>Other Books</head>
               <list>
                  <item><title>The Tragic Era</title> by <name><persName ref="#person039">Claude G. Bowers</persName></name> <measure type="price">$5.00</measure><name>Houghton Mifflin Company</name><name>The Riverside Press</name><placeName ref="#place008">Cambridge, Massachusetts</placeName></item>    
                  <item><title>You and Segregation</title> by <name><persName ref="#person040">Herman E. Talmadge</persName></name> <measure type="price">$1.00</measure><name>Vulcan Press, Incorporated</name><placeName ref="#place009">401 Fourth Street, S. W. Birmingham, Alabama</placeName></item> 
                  <item><title>American Race Theories</title> by <name><persName ref="#person041">Byram Campbell</persName></name> <measure type="price">$3.50</measure><name>Chapman and Grimes, Inc.</name><placeName ref="#place010">Boston, Massachusetts</placeName></item> 
                  <item><title>Take Your Choice</title> by <name><persName ref="#person042">Theodore Bilbo</persName></name> <measure type="price">$3.00</measure><name><!-- unsure if this is a person, it looks like it, but her name is where the other publishers are. --><persName ref="#person043">Miss Louise Lacy</persName></name><placeName ref="#place011">P.O. Box 1435, Jackson, Mississippi</placeName></item> 
                  <item><title>The Cult of Equality</title> by <name><persName ref="#person044">Stuart O. Landry</persName></name><measure type="price">$3.50</measure><name><persName ref="#person044">Mr. Stuart O. Landry</persName></name><placeName ref="#place012">305 Chartres Street, New Orleans, Louisiana</placeName></item> 
                  <item><title>White America</title> by <name><persName ref="#person045">Earnest Sevier Cox</persName></name> <measure type="price">$2.00</measure><name> <persName ref="#person045">Mr. Earnest Sevier Cox</persName></name><placeName ref="#place013">P.O. Box 116 Richmond, Virginia</placeName></item>
                  <item><title>The Sovereign States</title> by <name><persName ref="#person046">James J. Kilpatrick</persName></name> <measure type="price">$5.00</measure><name>The Henry Regnery Company</name><placeName ref="#place014">64 East Jackson Boulevard. Chicago Illinois</placeName></item> 
               </list>
               </div>
           <div type="article">
              <head>Finance Chairman's Report</head>
              <p>I wish I could tell you that we have a big cash balance,
                 that our membership has doubled or even tripled. I cannot
                 make any such statement.</p> 
              <p>It is to be expected that our people would be apathetic
                 because, I suppose, they feel there is nothing going on that
                 needs attention, and that we have nothing to worry about
                 here in <placeName ref="#place002">Mississippi</placeName>. This may or may not be true.</p>
              <p>The long term goal of this movement is to change the
                 outlook of people in the rest of the United States. We will be
                 able to maintain segregation in <placeName ref="#place002">Mississippi</placeName>, but unless we can
                 get laws changed or decisions reversed, this thing is going to
                 nag at us for the balance of time. As for myself, I am not
                 worried about integration in <placeName ref="#place002">Mississippi</placeName> in my life time. Lots
                 of us have children and grandchildren, and these children
                 and grandchildren are the ones I am thinking about. We
                 should keep a constant flow of facts going into other states,
                 and to do this takes money.</p>
              <p>Unquestionably, the Citizens' Council can claim credit
                 for initiating the fight against integration. Had not the Council
                 movement started when it did I feel we would already have
                 integration in some of our Southern states. Probably some
                 other movement would have come into being, but maybe it
                 would have been too late.</p>      
           </div>
            <div type="article">
               <head>Educational Fund</head>
               <p>The Educational Fund was incorporated <date>November 15,
                  1956</date>. The reason for the Educational Fund was that we were
                  not sure that contributions to the <orgName ref="#org001">Citizens' Council</orgName> were tax
                  exempt. We believe that since the Educational Fund of the
                  <orgName ref="#org002">NAACP</orgName> is tax exempt, the Educational Fund of the Citizens'
                  Council is tax exempt. So far the exemption has not come
                  through, but we have had no kick backs on former deduc-
                  tions. We believe that the Internal Revenue department must
                  declare it tax exempt.</p>
               <p>We wanted a fund so those people who can contribute in
                  large amounts could get tax exemptions, as this means a
                  great deal to many people.</p>
               <p>We are very careful how we handle the money in the
                  Educational Fund, and there is simply no way for the govern-
                  ment to declare it other than tax exempt. We hoped this fund
                  would be attractive to large contributors. So far we have had
                  only two individuals who have contributed $1,000 or more.</p>
               <p>We hope to have others.</p>
               <p><persName ref="#person026">ELLETT LAWRENCE</persName>, Finance Chairman</p>     
               <!-- I need to learn how to tag groups / organizations like the Citizens' Council and NAACP -->
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
